<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King. A proclamation declaring His Maiesties royall grace, to confirme to his subiects of the realme of Ireland, their defective titles, and to establish their estates and possessions by his commission vnder his great Seale of England.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B14168</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99891184</idno>
  <idno type="VID">185718</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240918356</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">STC 14220</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 506.h.11[128]</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99891184</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99891184e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B14168)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185718)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C2:2[129])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King. A proclamation declaring His Maiesties royall grace, to confirme to his subiects of the realme of Ireland, their defective titles, and to establish their estates and possessions by his commission vnder his great Seale of England.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by Robert Barker, printer to the Kings most excellent Maiestie: and by the assignes of Iohn Bill,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1630. [i.e. 1631]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated at end: Whitehall the fourteenth day of March, in the sixt yeere of our reigne.</note>
                  <note>The publication year is given according to Lady Day dating.</note>
                  <note>Arms 21; Steele notation: of  meanes  2) in  Estate.</note>
                  <note>Identified as STC 14220a on UMI microfilm reel 1244.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Titles of honor and nobility --  Law and legislation --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Nobility --  Law and legislation --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:185718:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <p>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</p>
                  <figDesc>England's royal coat of arms, 1630</figDesc>
                  <p>DIEV ET MON DROIT.</p>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>¶ By the King.</head>
            <head>¶ A Proclamation declaring His Maiesties Royall Grace, to confirme to His Subiects of the Realme of Ireland, their defectiue Titles, and to establish their Estates and Possessions by His <hi>Commission vnder his great Seale of</hi> England.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas the Kings most Excellent Maiestie out of His Princely care of</hi> the generall quiet, prosperity, and good of all His louing Subiects of all and euery His Realmes and Dominions, hath an equall respect and fauour to those His Subiects of <hi>Ireland,</hi> as to those of <hi>England,</hi> and vpon all iust occasi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, is, and will be ready and willing to expresse the same, and His Maiestie conceiuing, that there is no stronger motiue to inuite His Subiects of that Realme to submit themselues willingly to the Lawes, to entertaine peace, and conforme themselues to ciuility, industry, and good order, nor better meanes to make them opulent, rich, and happy, then by the generall setling and securing of their estates and possessions which is their liuelyhood: And His Maiesty finding that many petitioners resort from thence hither into <hi>England,</hi> for securing of their estates by new particuler Patents, and that there are dayly suitors heere to His Maiestie for grants of Lands in that Realme, vpon pretence of Concealments, Intrusions, or defectiue Titles, for obtaining of which grants, the Suitors offer large considerations by way of Fine, and increase of Rent, and other Seruices to the Crowne, to his Maiesties great aduantage, and some of these persons haue of late obtained Letters vnder the Priuie Signet, to passe part of the premisses by Letters Patents vnder the great Seale of that Realme of <hi>Ireland</hi> in Fee. His Maiestie of His infinite grace and goodnesse, foreseeing how full of danger and trouble it might bee to His good Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iects of that Realme, to giue way to such priuate Suits, although some profit should accrew there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out vnto His Crowne; And preferring in this point the generall quiet of His people before His owne benefit, hath been graciously pleased, not onely to make stay of passing the premisses, and all other Lands within that Realme, and of all Suits of that nature, but also out of His ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der care and respect of His said Subiects, and of their peace and prosperity, for their exceeding benefit, and yet with some expectation of profit for the increase of His owne Reuenue within that Realme, whereby Hee might the better support His ordinary charge there, and ease His people thereof, Hath thought meete in his Princely wisedome, to settle and secure for euer here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after their seuerall pretended Estates and possessions, by a Commission of grace vnder the great Seale of <hi>England,</hi> in very ample and beneficiall manner, and in such manner as by the like Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission of grace heere in <hi>England,</hi> for setling the possessions of His Subiects of this his Realme of <hi>England,</hi> as a marke of His equall fauour towards his Subiects of that Kingdome, as of this.</p>
            <p>His Maiesties gracious pleasure therefore is, and so hee doeth by this His Royall Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion declare the same, That if any of his Subiects of His sayd Realme of <hi>Ireland,</hi> doe, or shall
<pb facs="tcp:185718:2"/>conceiue, or feare their Estates or possessions to bee subiect to his Maiesties iust aduantage in Law or equity, They, before the first day of September next ensuing, are either in person, or by their Attourneys, or Agents sufficiently authorised and instructed by them, to make their repaire into this Realme of <hi>England,</hi> where they shall finde his Maiesties Commissioners ready to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertaine their seuerall Suites, and to whom if they shall resort, they may according to their seuerall Cases, settle and secure such their Estates and possessions as shall be defectiue or doubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full, according to such instructions as his Maiestie shall giue to His Commissioners to that pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose, and vpon such reasonable and gracious conditions, as the said Commissioners in their good discretions shal thinke fit, (without preiudicing any such future Plantations as shall be found iust and honourable for his Maiestie to proceede in) and for the safety and benefit of the Countrey, and shall stand with the quality of the seuerall Cases of such as shall become suitors, wherein they shall be receiued to make their finall peace and settlement of their Estates and possessions, either for a reasonable Composition in money, or new increase of Rent, and other Seruices, or for both, as shal be thought fittest, and be agreed vpon; and withal what shal be past vpon this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission, his Maiestie doeth hereby declare, that Hee will bee pleased to giue His Royall assent, aswell to confirme the same at the next Parliament to bee holden for that Kingdome; As also that the Statute of <hi>Vicesimo primo Iacobi Regis,</hi> made heere in <hi>England,</hi> for limiting His Highnesse Title to sixty yeeres, shall bee then enacted there, but the same to extend onely for the benefit of the Patentees that shall passe vpon the sayd Commission, and that all speede shall bee made for the dispatching of all the premisses vpon the sayd Commission, if they His sayd Subiects of <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> shall bee forward on their parts therein, to the end that the Parliament there may the soo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner begin.</p>
            <p>But his Maiestie doeth further declare his Royall pleasure by this His Proclamation, that Hee will take his iust aduantages against all such persons as shall neglect, by the time prefixed, to repayre hither, and in conuenient time after to compound for passing their Lands vpon the sayd Commission, and vpon such neglect his Maiestie resolues to dispose thereof for His best pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit, either to such persons as shall be Suitors for the same, or otherwise at His pleasure.</p>
            <p>And Hee doeth also by this his publike Declaration straitly charge and command, that vntill the sayd first day of September, and after as long as the sayd Commission shall bee continued heere for this seruice, No person or persons do presume to make suit vnto his Highnesse for Grants or Confirmations of Estates of any Lands or Hereditaments, or other matter touching his Estate or Reuenue within that Realme, nor passe any of the premisses but vpon the sayd Commission.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Giuen at Our Court at Whitehall <date>the fourteenth day of March, in the sixt yeere of Our Reigne.</date>
                  </hi>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <closer>God saue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings most Excellent Maiestie: and by the Assignes of Iohn Bill. 1630.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>